-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
我是菲比·布菲  我底下有宝宝要出来
I'm Phoebe Buffay, and I have babies coming out me.
好的  你开始阵痛了吗
Okay. Have you started having contractions?
还没  听说会很痛  真的吗
Not yet. I heard they really hurt. Do they hurt?
-这个嘛  -天哪
- Well... - Oh, my God!
哪一位是父亲
Which of you is the father?
他们都不是  我弟弟才是
None of them are. The father is my brother.
好吧
Okay.
我一定会很怀念你那样吓别人
I'm so gonna miss watching you freak people out like that.
菲比  这是将来要给宝宝看的
Pheebs, this is for the babies to look at someday.
在生产前你有话要说吗
So is there anything you want to say anything before it starts?
好的
Oh, okay.
孩子们  我是菲比姑姑
Hi, kids! It's me, Aunt Phoebe.
真想快点见到你们  请不要弄疼我
Can't wait to see you. Please don't hurt me!
你们怎么那么慢
What took you so long?
两辆计程车是一起出发的
Your cab left when ours did.
-我们回去拿我的外套  -是的
- We went back because I forgot my jacket. - That's right.
你没穿外套啊
You're not wearing a jacket.
真是的  我又忘了
Oh, man! I did it again!
得有人通知弗兰克和爱丽丝
We have someone has to call Frank and Alice.
我妈也想...  乔伊  你干什么
My mom might... Joey, what are you doing?
我得拍生产前的镜头
I've got to get the "before" shot!
菲比  我们问过护士了
Pheebs, okay, we spoke to the nurse.
你的医生之所以迟到
The reason your doctor is late...
是因为她不来了
...is because she's not coming.
-什么  -她在浴室跌倒撞到头
- What? - Apparently, she fell on the shower and hit her head.
天哪  那个笨女人
Oh, my God. She's so stupid!
菲比  不会有事的
Pheebs, it's gonna be okay.
你说得轻松
That's easy for you to say.
你的阴道又没有三个宝宝要出来
I don't see three kids coming out of your vagina!
亲爱的  听我说
Honey, listen. You know what,
护士说这个医生很好
the nurse said the doctor is wonderful.
他是妇产科主任
He's head of the department.
好吧  老天爷救救我
All right. Oh, dear God, save me!
-怎么了  -我的第一次阵痛来了
- What? - I'm having my first contraction!
哦  还不错
Oh, it's not bad.
生命的奇迹开始了  我...
And so the miracle of birth begins. And I...
你没事吧
You okay?
有个地方好痛
Something hurts.
爱的感同身受  好感人
It's sympathy pains. That's so sweet!
我不知道我有那么在意
I didn't know I cared that much.
-你好  -你好  菲比
- Hello. - Hi. Phoebe.
我是哈洛医生  我负责替你接生
I'm Dr. Harad. I'll be delivering your babies.
有我在你放心
I want you to know you'll be in good hands.
我的经验非常丰富
I've been doing this a long time.
我马上回来帮你做检查
I'll be back in a minute to do your internal.
放松就行了  目前一切都很好
and meantime just relax, because everything here looks great.
还有  我爱方奇(电视剧《欢乐时光》里的人物)
And also, I love Fonzie.
他刚才说  他爱方奇吗
Did he just say he loves Fonzie?
听起来是
That's what it sounded like.
好吧
All right.
我来晚了吗  还没人出来吧
Am I late? Nobody came out yet, right?
没有  还没开始呢  爱丽丝呢
No, we haven't started yet. Where's Alice?
在特拉华州  不过她正在赶来
Delaware. She's on her way though.
在她来之前  由我充当你的呼吸指导
So until she gets here, I'll be your coach.
放心  她有教我拉什么马自达呼吸法
Don't worry. She told me about the la-Mazada stuff.
就是在月底前生孩子
That's when you get the baby out by the end of the month
就能获得2%的优惠
they give you two percent financing.
是的
Yeah.
莫妮卡  你一定会为我感到骄傲
Monica, you're gonna be very proud of me.
我帮我们约到了两个俏护士
I just got us dates with two unbelievably cute nurses.
精彩
Oh, my!
是男护士
They're male nurses.
在我想象中不是
Not in my head.
总之他们约我们周六晚上出去  如何
Anyway, they want to take us out Saturday night! What do you say?
我看算了
I don't think so.
什么叫算了
What? What are you talking about?
是你劝我忘记罗斯向前看的
You're the one been telling me to get over Ross and move on.
我向前看了  你得陪我
I'm moving on and you're moving on with me.
告诉我一个你不去的理由
Come on, give me one reason why don't you want to go?
不如你说一个你认为的好理由
Why don't you give me something that would be a good reason...
我再告诉你是不是好理由
...and I'll tell you if it's true.
-什么  -没那么简单吧
- What? - Harder than it sounds, isn't it?
你也要去
Okay. You're coming with me.
我还说  如果他们下班时我们还没走
And I also told them if we still here when they get off...
就一起去餐厅吃果冻
we'll go down the cafeteria and gets some Jello with them.
对啊  人永远吃得下果冻
Yeah, there's always room for Jello.
乔伊  你为什么能说得那么色
Joey, how do you make that dirty?
简单  我什么都能说得很色
It's easy. I can do it with anything. Watch.
奶奶的鸡肉沙拉
Grandma's chicken salad...
罗斯  拍这个
Ross. Get a shot of this.
宝宝们
Hi babies.
这是你们出生当天的报纸头条
These are the headlines on the day when you were born.
现在女宝宝把头转开  男宝宝们
Now, girl baby, turn away. And boy babies...
看这个
...check it out!
这就是你们出生当月的裸女
This is what naked women looked like the month when you were born.
尽情欣赏吧
Now let's dive into the good stuff.
好  阵痛又来了
Okay, I'm having another one!
这次也不太痛  错  很痛
This one doesn't hurt eith... Yes, it does!
我有点希望已经生了
I was kind of hoping that was it.
莫妮卡和瑞秋呢
Where are Monica and Rachel, anyway?
两个护士约她们出去  可能跟护士在一起
A couple of nurses asked them out. Maybe they're with them.
真的  男护士吗
Really? Male nurses?
对  我也很失望
Yeah, I was bummed too.
他们要去约会
So they're going on dates.
-什么时候  -星期六吧
- When? - I think Saturday.
-他怎么了  -爱的感同身受
- What's with him? - Sympathy pains.
我本来很感动
I thought it was really sweet at first,
但现在我觉得他只是想抢风头
but now I think he's just trying to steal my thunder.
-检查了  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
来看看你的情况
Let's see what we got here.
你知道吗  方奇跟三胞胎约会过
Oh, you know, Fonzie dated triplets.
你一直提到的这位方奇
This Fonzie person you keep referring to...
是另一位医生吗
...is that another doctor?
不是不是
Oh, no, no.
方奇是亚瑟·方塞瑞利的昵称
Fonzie is the nickname of Arthur Fonzerelli.
也叫方子
The Fonz.
好
All right.
其实不会很怪吧
It's not that weird, is it?
怪得不得了
It's very weird!
我才不要听某人告诉我
I don't want some guy down there telling me
宫口扩张了"一滴滴"
I'm "dilated-a-mundo."
说句公道话  他可没有模仿方奇
To be fair, he doesn't seem to be impersonating Fonzie...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
干嘛替他辩解  帮我再找一位医生
Why are you defending him? Just get me another doctor.
没有发疯的  也不是方奇的医生
One who is not crazy and who is not Fonzie!
其实他不是...
Again, it's not he...
嘿  你在这里
Hey, there you are!
有件事应该让你知道
Listen, I think there's something you should know.
是你要跟护士约会的事吗  我听乔伊说了
Is this about you dating the nurse? Joey told me.
我一点也不在意  你和我又没什么
I am so fine. You and I, we're just nothing.
我们只是玩玩
Just goofing around.
其实我是想告诉你  我不打算去
Acutally, I was about to tell you I was going to get out of it.
既然我们只是"玩玩"
But if we're just "goofing around,"
那我就跟他出去好了
then maybe I will go out with him.
好  也许我也会
Fine. Maybe I will too.
嘿  看我在礼品店发现了什么
Hey! You guys, look what I found in the gift shop.
起来  快起来
Get up! Get up! Get up!
菲比  这是欧伯曼医生
Okay, Pheebs, this is Dr. Oberman.
他对方奇及其他《欢乐时光》人物
He has no strong feelings about Fonzie...
都没什么感觉
...or any of the Happy Days gang.
你好  你要升几年级了
Hi. You're going into what grade?
我是住院医师第一年  经常有人说我年轻
I'm actually a first-year resident. I got that a lot.
我提前毕业了
I graduated early.
我也是
Me too.
罗斯
Ross,
或许我应该强调  我是要成年的医师
maybe I should have specified I'd need a grown-up doctor.
我绝对有能力...
Really, I'm fully qualified...
小子
Doogie!
到底有没有人了解我快生了
Does anybody understand that I'm going to be having babies soon?
你走  小毛头  走啊
Go, little boy! Go!
酷  你把他弄哭了
Oh, cool. You made him cry!
崔比安尼先生  你有肾结石
Mr. Tribbiani, I'm afraid you've got kidney stones.
有别的可能吗
Well, what else could it be?
就是肾结石
It's kidney stones.
或是
Or...
肾结石
Kidney stones.
差不多了
You're getting there.
这些宝宝非常非常幸运
You know these babies are very, very lucky.
是吗  为什么
They are? Why?
他们的生日日期是方子的一半
They have the honor be born on the Fonz's half-birthday.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
我澄清一下
Just to clarify...
我不是方奇
...I'm not Fonzie.
说真的  你能为你弟弟两口子
I just need to tell you I think it's such a terrific thing that
生孩子真是太了不起了
you're having these babies for Frank and Alice.
是啊  的确
No, it is.
-我可以告诉你一个秘密吗  -说吧
- Can I tell you a secret? - Yeah.
我想自己留一个
I want to keep one.
天哪  我会上新闻的
Oh, I'm gonna be on the news.
菲比  别开玩笑了
Phoebe, honey, you got be kidding.
你明知你不能这么做
You know you can't keep one of these babies.
为什么不行  也许我可以  你怎么知道
Why not? Maybe I can. You don't know.
我当然知道
Yes, yes, I do. I do know.
弗兰克和爱丽丝他们一定三个都要
Frank and Alice are gonna want to keep all their children.
不一定  知道吗
Maybe not. You know?
说真的  三个宝宝太多了
Seriously, three babies are a handful.
也许他们正想找机会摆脱掉一个
Maybe they're looking a chance to unload one of them.
我不想因为没开口而失去机会
I hate to miss an opportunity because I didn't ask.
菲比  不行  这太疯狂了
Phoebe, no. This is insane.
你就问问看嘛
Just ask him.
什么  我
What? Me?
我不能去问他
I can't ask him!
你知道那样多不成体统吗
Do you have any idea how inappropriate that would be?
总之你去找弗兰克谈
All I'm saying is, just talk to Frank, okay?
探探他的口风
Just feel him out.
不行  我不会叫弗兰克给你一个孩子的
No forget it. I'm not gonna ask Frank to give you one of his kids.
你说得对
You're right.
就说是你要的
Tell him it's for you.
好一点了吗  亲爱的
Feeling better, sweetie?
一点点吧
Maybe a little.
真希望你没看到我吐
Wish you hadn't seen me throw up.
我也希望
Me too.
我刚刚听说  怎么回事
I just heard. What's up?
肾结石
Kidney stones!
通常  崔比安尼先生
Ordinarily, Mr Tribbiani,
我们会用冲击波震碎结石
we try to break the stones up with shock waves.
但你的结石太靠近膀胱了
But they're too close to the bladder now.
所以要么等你排出体外
Which means we can either wait for you to pass them
要么从尿道往上...
or else go up the urethra...
不行不行  不能往上  明白吗
No, no, no, no. Nothing is going up, okay? Up...
绝对不考虑往上  尿道是什么
Up is not an option. What's a urethra?
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你问他了吗
Did you ask him?
我还没有机会跟他独处
No, I haven't had a chance be alone with him yet.
我的时间有限
I'm kind of on a clock here.
哦  方奇
Oh, Fonzie.
你知道我一直喜欢谁吗  默克
You know who I always liked? Mork.
收回收回
Undo it. Undo it.
方奇遇见默克
Fonzie met Mork.
默克把方奇冻住了
Mork froze Fonzie.
是的
Yeah.
是的  但是
Yes, but...
但是方奇本来就很酷(冷)
Fonzie was already cool.
所以他不会有事  对吧
So he wasn't hurt. Right?
也对
Yeah, that's right.
你好吗
How you doing?
很好  医生说随时都会生
Okay. Doctor says any minute now.
爱丽丝马上就会到
You know, Alice is going to be here so soon.
你能不能帮个忙  先憋住
You couldn't just do me a favor and, like, hold them in?
抱歉  弗兰克
Sorry, Frank,
我正在处理你请我帮的上一个忙
I'm kind in the middle of the last favor you asked me to do.
-嘿  -嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
-瑞秋  -莫妮卡  他是丹
- Rachel. - Monica, this is Dan,
我们星期六的约会对象
one of the guys we're gonna be going out with on Saturday.
丹  这是莫妮卡
Dan, Monica.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你好  丹
Hello, Dan.
我很期待星期六的约会  非常期待
I'm really looking forward to Saturday night. Really! Really!
丹
So, Dan...
你是护士不是医生啊
...nurse, not a doctor, huh?
有点娘娘腔对吧
Kind of girlie, isn't it?
钱德勒
Chandler!
没关系
That's okay.
我只是在读医学院的同时  勤工俭学
I'm just doing this to put myself through medical school.
而且海湾战争时  感觉也没那么娘娘腔
And it didn't feel so "girlie" during the Gulf War.
那当然
Sure.
感谢你保家卫国
Listen, thanks for doing that for us, by the way.
何必等到星期六  你明天有空吗
So why wait till Saturday? Are you free tomorrow?
行啊  我找人代班
Sure. I'll get somebody to cover me my shift.
太好了
Great!
我们星期六去约个会如何
Hey, how about you and me, Saturday night?
-不要  -很好  非常好
- No. - All right, very good!
这一回很痛
This is a big one.
把它们弄出来
Get these things out of me!
深呼吸  深呼吸可以止痛
Breathe! Breathe through the pain.
我想吃止痛药  罗斯  我想吃止痛药
I want the drugs, Ross! I want the drugs!
我也是  我也是
I do too! I do too!
我爱你  再见
Yeah, I love you. Okay, bye.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
爱丽丝她妈妈说  她出发五小时了
That was Alice's mom. She said that she left five hours ago.
她现在应该到了
She should be here by now.
亲爱的  别担心  她会赶上的
Honey, don't worry, she's gonna make it on time.
-是啊  -是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
弗兰克
So, Frank...
三个宝宝啊  还真多  对吧
...three babies. That just seems like a lot, huh?
我不觉得
Not to me.
很好
Fair enough.
扩张了十公分  该生了
Okay, you're at ten centimeters. Time to start having babies.
请父亲留下来就好
I want only the father here please.
-我们爱你  -好运
- We love you. - Good luck.
-拜  丹  -拜  莫妮卡
- Bye, Dan. - Bye, Monica.
我要产钳  消毒毛巾和31频道
All right, I need a clamp, a sterile towel and Channel 31.
那是什么
What is that?
天哪
Oh, my God!
不不  这一集很好看  方奇会打手鼓
Oh, no, no! It's a good one. Fonzie plays the bongos.
准备好了吗  是时候用力了
All right, ready? It's time to try pushing.
准备好了吗  是时候小便了
Are you ready? It's time to try peeing.
等等  是差不多时候小便了
Wait, wait, wait, wait! It's almost time to try peeing.
用力  很好  专心用力
You know push. That's it push, just concentrate on pushing.
-很好  -我看到头了
- Here we go. - I see the head.
万岁  他有头
Yes, it has a head!
继续用力  加油
Keep pushing. Come on.
不敢相信有人从你身体里出来
I can't believe somebody's coming out of you right now!
有人从你身体里出来
There's somebody coming out of you!
-是我儿子  -没错
- It's my son! - All right.
这是你的第一个宝宝
Here's your first baby!
万岁  儿子出来了
Yes! We got a baby boy!
弗兰克二世二世
Frank Junior, Junior!
他长得怎样
How does he look?
恶心死了
So gross!
好  可以再用力了吗
Okay. You ready to push again?
我已经生一个了  不要烦我
I already had a baby. Leave me alone!
加油  你一定行  你一定行
Okay, okay, come on, you can do it! You can do it!
小莱丝莉出来了  又生了一个
Little Leslie's here! We got another one!
天哪  我居然有两个孩子了
Oh, my God! I can't believe I have two children.
真吓人
How scary is that?
快啊  小钱德勒  该出来了
Come on, little Chandler, it's time to be born.
快啊  小钱德勒  出来啊
Come on, little Chandler. Come on!
他出来了  太好了  他出来了
He's coming! Yes, he's coming!
嘿  他的小鸡鸡呢
Hey, where's his thing?
钱德勒是女孩
Chandler's a girl!
天哪  幼稚园回忆重现
Oh, God! Kindergarten flashback.
肯定是做超声波检查时看错了
They must read the sonogram wrong,
医生以为是个男孩
because they thought it was a boy.
但钱德勒是女孩  钱德勒是女孩
But Chandler's a girl! But Chandler's a girl!
很好  继续叫吧
Okay, keep saying it.
-我来晚了吗  -不会  一切都很好
- Am I too late? - No, no. Everything's okay.
孩子们都很健康
Everybody is health.
有三十个手指和三十个脚趾
There's 30 fingers and 30 toes.
我们有孩子了
We have our babies?
是的
Yeah.
我们有孩子了
We have our babies.
天哪
Oh, my God!
你办到了
You did it, man.
你要看看它们吗
Would you like to see them?
它们好小哦
They're so small.
-我明天跟你联络  -好
- So I'll call you tomorrow. - Great.
你真的要跟那个男护士约会吗
So are you really gonna go out with that nurse man?
你和我只是"玩玩"
You and I are just "goofing around."
我当然也可以跟他"玩玩"
I thought, why not "goof around" with him?
我不知道你有没有在词典里
I don't know if you've looked up the term
查过"玩玩"这个词
"goofing around" in the dictionary.
我有
Well, I have...
这个词的定义是
...and the technical definition is:
两个好朋友  非常在乎对方
Two friends who care a lot about each other...
在床上很"性"福
...and have amazing sex...
而且想多跟对方相处
...and just want to spend more time together.
如果你用的是让你生气的词典版本
But if you have this new dictionary that gets you mad at me...
那应该给你买本  我那种版本的
...then we have to get you my original dictionary.
我实在很不擅长这个
I am so bad at this.
-比你想象的要好  -真的
- You're better than you think you are. - Really?
好  那…
Okay. So if...?
-要见好就收  -我也觉得够了
- Know when to stop.  - I sensed that I should stop.
-我们没事了吧  -没事
- So we're okay? - Yeah.
我去告诉丹  我不会跟他约会的
I'm gonna go tell Dan that it's not gonna happen.
-不要跳舞  -好
- Don't do the dance. - Right.
我想我最喜欢你
I think you're my favorite.
-你抱的是哪一个  -无所谓
- Which one do you have? - I don't care.
弗兰克和爱丽丝要我告诉你
So Frank and Alice want me to tell you
他们还要在外面打电话
they're still outside making phone calls.
你有没有问他们那件事
Did you talk to them about, you know...
问了
Yeah.
没有  亲爱的
No, honey.
没事
Oh, okay.
反正也不太可能
It was a long shot.
伙计们  让我跟宝宝们独处一下好吗
You guys? Can I just have a second alone with the babies?
好的
Oh, yeah.
你们都在了
So here you are.
我对着培养皿跟你们说话  仿佛是昨天的事
Seems like yesterday I was talking to you in that petri dish.
大家都说生产最难熬
Everyone said labor was the hardest thing I ever have to do.
其实跟你们分开才是
But they were wrong. This is.
这段日子真的很开心
Well, I had the most fun with you guys.
真想带你们回家  每天看着你们
I wish I could take you home and see you every day.
我就当你们最喜欢的姑姑吧
Okay, I'll settle for being your favorite aunt.
爱丽丝的妹妹家有游泳池
I know Alice's sister has a pool,
但你们在我肚子里游过
but you lived in me.
那就这样了
Okay, so we're cool.
我们会处得很好
We're gonna be great.
击掌
Little high-fives.
既然你都哭了
Well, if you're gonna cry...
菲比  我们真为你骄傲  你好了不起
Phoebe, we are so proud of you. You're amazing!
我知道
I know.
真的有大家说的那么痛吗
So does it really hurt as bad as they say?
是的  你绝对受不了
Yeah, you won't be able to take it.
既然小钱德勒是个女孩
So now that little Chandler turn out be a girl,
他们打算叫她什么
what'll they name her?
就叫她钱德勒
They'll call her Chandler.
这个名字有点男性化吧
Kind of a masculine name, don't you think?
你都能用了
It works on you.